Guide to the Albert Galloway Keller Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1894-1952; Series II; 9.25 linear feet (26 boxes)
  - Essays, Lectures and Notebooks
    - Essay: "The Citizen's Dilemma", TMs, 1944 December 17 (Box 38, Folder 1032)
    - Essay: "No Man Pursueth?", TMs, 1944 December 20 (Box 38, Folder 1033)
    - Essay: "Diplomacy", TMs, 1944 December 22 (Box 38, Folder 1034)
    - Essay: "A Check-Rein for Authority", TMs, 1944 December 28 (Box 38, Folder 1035)
    - Letter to the editor of The Register, printed, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 1036)
    - Essay: "All of Us the Real Indispensables", TMs (Box 38, Folder 1037)
    - Essay: "All of Us the Real Indispensables", proofsheets (Box 38, Folder 1038-1039)
    - Essay: "All-of-Us the Real Indispensables", printed, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 1040)
    - Book review of Richard Hofstader's Social Darwinism in American Thought, TMs, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 1041)
    - Essay: "What of 'Experience'", AMs and TMs, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 1042)
    - Essay: "The Demotion of Enemy Morale", TMs, 1942-1944 (Box 38, Folder 1043)
    - Essay: "English Teaching and the Classics", AMs and TMs, 1945 January 20 (Box 38, Folder 1044)
    - Essay: "Risks and Risk-Takers", TMs, 1945 January 25 (Box 38, Folder 1045)
    - Essay: "Mr. Dorland Smith", TMs, 1945 February 7 (Box 39, Folder 1046)
    - Essay: "Perspective on War", printed, 1945 February (Box 39, Folder 1047)
    - Essay: "The Symbols of Cultural Survival", printed, 1945 March 17 (Box 39, Folder 1048)
    - Letter to the editor of the Register, TMs, 1945 May 7 (Box 39, Folder 1049)
    - Essay: "English Teaching and the Classics", printed, 1945 July 28 (Box 39, Folder 1050)
    - Essay: "The Place of Fear in the Scheme of Things", TMs, 1945 August 26 (Box 39, Folder 1051)
    - Essay: "The Fallacy of the 'Lost Year?'", printed, 1945 August (Box 39, Folder 1052)
    - Essay: "What Did Darwin Really Say?", printed, 1945 October 6 (Box 39, Folder 1053)
    - Essay: "Lightmindedness", TMs, 1941-1945 (Box 39, Folder 1054)
    - Essay: "In Defense of a Certain German", TMs, 1941-1945 (Box 39, Folder 1055)
    - Essay on World War II and domestic policies, Ams, 1941-1945 (Box 39, Folder 1056)
    - Essay: "'Gratitude' between Nations", TMs, 1944-1945 (Box 39, Folder 1057)
    - Essay: "What Penalty", TMs, 1944-1945 (Box 39, Folder 1058)
    - Essay: "A Misbegotten Term", TMs, 1944-1945[?] (Box 39, Folder 1059)
    - Essay: "How Law, International as Well as Local, Begins", TMs, 1945-1946[?] (Box 39, Folder 1060)
    - Letter to the editor of the Herald-Tribune, TMs, 1946 April 28 (Box 39, Folder 1061)
    - Essay: "The Place of Fear in the Scheme of Things", printed, 1946 July (Box 39, Folder 1062)
    - Essay: "The Historic Gap", TMs, 1946 December 22 (Box 39, Folder 1063)
    - Letter to the editor of the Herald-Tribune, TMs, 1946[?] (Box 39, Folder 1064)
    - Essay: "The Rash Challenge to Natural Law", AMs, 1947 August 6 (Box 39, Folder 1065)
    - Essay: "The Fix We Are In", TMs, 1947 (Box 39, Folder 1066)
    - Letter to the editor of the, TMs, 1948 May 29 (Box 39, Folder 1067)
    - Essay: "Day", AMs, 1948 July 9 (Box 39, Folder 1068)
    - Essay: "Education: in Retrospect", AMs, 1950 November 13 (Box 39, Folder 1069)
    - Essay: "Education: in Retrospect", abstract of first draft, TMs, 1950 November 13 (Box 39, Folder 1070)
    - Essay: "Education?", TMs, 1950 November 16 (Box 39, Folder 1071)
    - Book review of Arnold Bergstraesser's Goethe and the Modern Age, TMs, 1950 (Box 39, Folder 1072)
    - Book review of Douglas MacArthur's Revitalizing a Nation, printed, 1952 July 11 (Box 39, Folder 1073)
    - Essay: "The Shame of It", TMs, 1952 July 14 (Box 39, Folder 1074)
    - Essay: "The Neurosis of Timidity", AMs, 1952 September 23 (Box 39, Folder 1075)
    - Essay: "The Neurosis of Timidity", TMs, 1952 September 23 (Box 39, Folder 1076)
    - Book review of Kenneth Williams' Lincoln Finds a General, AMs and TMs, 1952 November 29 (Box 39, Folder 1077)
    - Essay: "The Record and the Wriggle", TMs, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 1078)
    - Essay: "On Reconciling the Irreconcilable", TMs, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 1079)
    - Letter to the editor of the Nation, printed, n.y. January 2 (Box 39, Folder 1080)
    - Letter to the editor of The Evening Post, n.y. August 3 (Box 39, Folder 1081)
    - Essay: "What Literature Can Do for Science", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1082)
    - Essay: "How Not to Do It", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1083)
    - Essay: "History Is Shadow-Soup", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1084)
    - Book review of the Today and Tomorrow series, TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1085)
    - Essay on the devaluation of the dollar, AMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1086)
    - Essay: "Foresight, Hindsight, Insight", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1087)
    - Essay: "On 'Ideologies'", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1088)
    - Essay: "Survivals", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1089)
    - Essay: "Difficult Navigation for the Historical Novel", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1090)
    - Letter to the editor of The Evening Post, undated (Box 39, Folder 1091)
    - Essay on the social sciences, AMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1092)
    - Essay: "Forgotten Man's' Task is Pray Some, Pay Much", printed, undated (Box 39, Folder 1093)
    - Book review of Charles A. Beard's The Nature of the Social Sciences, TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1094)
    - Essay: "The Cultural Survival", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1095)
    - Essay: "When Doctors Disagree", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1096)
    - Essay: "Criticism, Plain and Fancy", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1097)
    - Essay supporting better: salaries for nurses, TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1098)
    - Essay: "Sketch of a Proposed Ethnography", AMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1099)
    - Essay: "Post-War Planning in a Democracy", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1100)
    - Essay: "Tradition vs. Conviction in a Democracy", AMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1101)
    - Essay: "Uncertainty", AMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1102)
    - Essay: "Can the People Think?", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1103)
    - Essay: "Concerning Euthanasia for the Hopelessly Defective", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1104)
    - Essay: "On Obligations 'Within the Family'", undated (Box 39, Folder 1105)
    - Essay comparing World War II to an Athletic, Event", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1106)
    - Essay on the standard of living and the wastes of war, undated (Box 39, Folder 1107)
    - Essay: "A Few Teachings about Common Sense", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1108)
    - Essay: "Some Ideas about Property", AMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1109)
    - Essay: "The Taming of Fire", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1110)
    - Essay: "In Praise of the Closable Mind", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1111)
    - Essay fragment: "Birth Control", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1112)
    - Essay; "The Limits of Eugenics", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1113)
    - Report on Turner's Cultural Traditions, undated (Box 39, Folder 1114)
    - Essay on the "Forgotten Man", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1115)
    - Essay: "Home Education", early draft, TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1116)
    - Essay: "Home Education", final draft, TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1117)
    - Essay: "A New Deal Distinction", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1118)
    - Letter to the editor of the Outlook, TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1119)
    - Essay: "Still Galvanizing the Defunct", TMs, undated (Box 39, Folder 1120)
    - Lecture notes on systems of sociology, undated (Box 39, Folder 1121)
    - Essay fragments: unidentified, undated (Box 39, Folder 1122)
    - Critiques of Keller's essays, undated (Box 39, Folder 1123)
    - Essay on ideologies, AMs, undated (Box 40, Folder 1124)
    - Essay: "The Square Old Uncle", AMs and TMs, undated (Box 40, Folder 1125)
    - Essay: "The Perils of Enlightenment", proofsheets, undated (Box 40, Folder 1126)
    - Essay: "Farming as a Science", AMs, undated (Box 40, Folder 1127)
    - Essay: "On Avoiding a National Swell Head", AMs, undated (Box 40, Folder 1128)
    - Essay: "Tentative Plea of the American Army as a School of Americanism", AMs, undated (Box 40, Folder 1129)
    - Essay: "Farming", AMs, undated (Box 40, Folder 1130)
    - Lecture Outline on social evolution, AMs and TMs, undated (Box 40, Folder 1131)
    - Essay: "Service and Self Respect", TMs, undated (Box 40, Folder 1132)
    - Essay: "Insurance", AMs, undated (Box 40, Folder 1133)
    - Essay fragment: "The Cultural Survival", AMs, undated (Box 40, Folder 1134)
  - Miscellaneous Writings
    - Chronological list of William G. Sumner's articles in The Independent, 1886-1891 (Box 41, Folder 1135)
    - Bibliography of Keller's writings by Keller, 1907[?] (Box 41, Folder 1136)
    - Proposed draft by Keller of a publishing contract with Ginn & Company, 1909 September 27 (Box 41, Folder 1137)
    - Keller recollections of his meeting with President Hadley of Yale, 1910 December 27 (Box 41, Folder 1138)
    - Description of the Sumner manuscripts in Keller's possession, 1914 (Box 41, Folder 1139)
    - Progress report on the preparation of Science of Society, 1917 (Box 41, Folder 1140)
    - Transcript of Keller's interview with Mussolini, [1930-1931?] (Box 41, Folder 1141)
    - Miscellaneous memoranda and notes, 1918-1947, undated (Box 41, Folder 1142-1143)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 41, Folder 1144)
    - Keller's description of the Sumner manuscripts donated to Yale College, AMs, undated (Box 41, Folder 1145)
    - "Provisional Contents of 'Protectionism and Other Essays'", undated (Box 41, Folder 1146)
    - Chapter entitled "Numbers" from unidentified book, AMs and TMs (Box 41, Folder 1147)
    - Guide to Keller's notecard filing system, undated (Box 41, Folder 1148)
    - Bibliography of William Graham Sumner's Writings, by A. G. Keller, undated (Box 41, Folder 1149)
    - Memorandum: "Condition of Sumner Materials, when Received", undated (Box 41, Folder 1150)
    - Will of Albert G. Keller, 1905 March 25 (Box 41, Folder 1151)
    - Keller fragments (Box 41, Folder 1152)
- Gradebooks and Examinations, 1900-1941; Series III; 3.1 linear feet (8 boxes)
  Gradebooks is arranged chronologically. (The entire section will not be available to researchers until 2016.)
  Examinations is arranged alphabetically by course.
  - Gradebooks
    Conditions Governing Access
    These records are restricted until January 1, 2016.
    - Industrial History, 1900-1901 (Box 42, Folder 1153)
    - Social Science, 1901-1902 (Box 42, Folder 1154)
    - Anthropology, Economics, Colonization, 1901-1902 (Box 42, Folder 1155)
    - Anthropology (Sheffield Scientific School) and Industrial History, 1902 (Box 42, Folder 1156)
    - Anthropology, Industrial History, Colonization, Ethnology, Commercial Geography, 1902-1903 (Box 42, Folder 1157)
    - Anthropology, Commercial Geography, Ethnology, 1903-1904 (Box 42, Folder 1158)
    - Science of Society, 1903-1904 (Box 42, Folder 1159)
    - Social Science, 1904-1905 (Box 42, Folder 1160)
    - Anthropology (Sheffield Scientific School) and Colonization, 1904-1905 (Box 42, Folder 1161)
    - Social Science, 1905 (Box 42, Folder 1162)
    - Anthropology (Sheffield Scientific School) and Colonization, 1905-1906 (Box 42, Folder 1163)
    - Anthropology, first term, 1906 (Box 42, Folder 1164)
    - Untitled, 1906, 1906[?] (Box 42, Folder 1165-1166)
    - Social Science, second term, 1906 (Box 42, Folder 1167)
    - Anthropology (Sheffield Scientific School) and Colonization, 1906-1907 (Box 42, Folder 1168)
    - Anthropology, second term, 1907 (Box 42, Folder 1169)
    - Colonization, 1907-1908 (Box 42, Folder 1170)
    - Anthropology and Social Evolution (Sheffield Scientific School), 1907-1908 (Box 42, Folder 1171)
    - Anthropology, 1907-1908 (Box 42, Folder 1172)
    - Anthropology (Sheffield Scientific School), 1908-1909 (Box 43, Folder 1173)
    - Anthropology, 1908-1910 (Box 43, Folder 1174-1175)
    - Anthropology and Social Evolution (Sheffield Scientific School), 1909-1910 (Box 43, Folder 1176)
    - Anthropology (Sheffield Scientific School), 1910 (Box 43, Folder 1177)
    - Anthropology, 1910-1911 (Box 43, Folder 1178-1179)
    - Science of Society, 1909-1910 (Box 43, Folder 1180)
    - Social Evolution, 1910-1911 (Box 43, Folder 1180)
    - Anthropology, 1911 (Box 43, Folder 1181)
    - Anthropology (Sheffield Scientific School), 1911 (Box 43, Folder 1182-1183)
    - Science of Society and Social Evolution (Sheffield Scientific School), 1911-1912 (Box 43, Folder 1184)
    - Anthropology, 1912 (Box 43, Folder 1185)
    - Anthropology and Social Evolution (Sheffield Scientific School), 1912-1913 (Box 43, Folder 1186)
    - Anthropology, 1912-1914 (Box 43, Folder 1187-1188)
    - Science of Society, 1913-1914 (Box 43, Folder 1189)
    - Social Evolution (Sheffield Scientific School), 1913-1914 (Box 43, Folder 1190)
    - Anthropology, 1914 (Box 43, Folder 1191)
    - Science of Society, 1914-1915 (Box 43, Folder 1192)
    - Social Evolution (Sheffield Scientific School), 1914-1915 (Box 44, Folder 1193)
    - Anthropology, 1914-1915 (Box 44, Folder 1194-1195)
    - Science of Society (Sheffield Scientific School), 1915-1916 (Box 44, Folder 1196)
    - Anthropology, 1915-1916 (Box 44, Folder 1197)
    - Science of Society, 1915-1916 (Box 44, Folder 1198)
    - Anthropology, 1916 (Box 44, Folder 1199-1200)
    - Science of Society (Sheffield Scientific School), 1916 (Box 44, Folder 1201)
    - Anthropology, 1916-1917 (Box 44, Folder 1202-1203)
    - Science of Society (Sheffield Scientific School), 1916-1917 (Box 44, Folder 1204)
    - Anthropology, 1917 (Box 44, Folder 1205)
    - Science of Society, 1917-1918 (Box 44, Folder 1206)
    - Anthropology, 1917-1918 (Box 44, Folder 1207)
    - Sheffield Scientific School, 1918 (Box 44, Folder 1208)
    - Science of Society, 1919 (Box 44, Folder 1209)
    - Science of Society (Sheffield Scientific School), 1919 (Box 44, Folder 1210)
    - Anthropology, 1919 (Box 44, Folder 1211-1212)
    - Science of Society, 1919-1920 (Box 44, Folder 1213)
    - Anthropology (Sheffield Scientific School), 1919-1920 (Box 45, Folder 1214)
    - Anthropology, 1919-1920 (Box 45, Folder 1215)
    - Science of Society (Sheffield Scientific School), 1919-1921 (Box 45, Folder 1216-1217)
    - Anthropology, 1920-1921 (Box 45, Folder 1218-1220)
    - Science of Society, 1921-1922 (Box 45, Folder 1221-1222)
    - Anthropology, 1922-1924 (Box 45, Folder 1223-1226)
    - Anthropology (Sheffield Scientific School), 1923-1924 (Box 45, Folder 1227)
    - Anthropology, 1923-1924 (Box 45, Folder 1228)
    - Science of Society, 1925 (Box 45, Folder 1229)
    - Anthropology, 1925 (Box 45, Folder 1230)
    - Science of Society, 1925-1926 (Box 45, Folder 1231)
    - Anthropology, 1925-1926 (Box 45, Folder 1232)
    - Untitled, 1925-1926 (Box 45, Folder 1233)
    - Anthropology, 1926-1927 (Box 45, Folder 1234-1236)
    - Untitled, 1927 (Box 46, Folder 1237)
    - Anthropology, 1927-1928 (Box 46, Folder 1238-1241)
    - Science of Society, 1927-1929 (Box 46, Folder 1242-1245)
    - Anthropology, 1928-1929 (Box 46, Folder 1246-1247)
    - Science of Society, 1929-1930 (Box 46, Folder 1248-1250)
    - Anthropology, 1929-1930 (Box 46, Folder 1251)
    - Science of Society, 1930-1932 (Box 46, Folder 1252-1256)
    - Anthropology, 1931-1932 (Box 46, Folder 1257)
    - Science of Society, 1931-1932 (Box 46, Folder 1258)
    - Anthropology, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 1259)
    - Science of Society, 1932-1933 (Box 46, Folder 1260-1261)
    - Science of Society, 1932-1933 (Box 47, Folder 1262)
    - Anthropology, 1932-1934 (Box 47, Folder 1263-1266)
    - Science of Society, 1933-1934 (Box 47, Folder 1267-1268)
    - Anthropology, 1933-1934 (Box 47, Folder 1269-1270)
    - Science of Society, 1934-1935 (Box 47, Folder 1271-1272)
    - Anthropology, 1934-1935 (Box 47, Folder 1273-1276)
    - Science of Society, 1934-1936 (Box 47, Folder 1277)
    - Anthropology, 1935-1936 (Box 47, Folder 1278-1279)
    - Science of Society, 1935-1937 (Box 47, Folder 1280-1281)
    - Anthropology, 1936-1937 (Box 47, Folder 1282-1284)
    - Science of Society, 1937-1938 (Box 47, Folder 1285)
    - Science of Society, 1937-1938 (Box 48, Folder 1286-1287)
    - Anthropology, 1937-1938 (Box 48, Folder 1288-1289)
    - Science of Society, 1938-1939 (Box 48, Folder 1290-1291)
    - Anthropology, 1938-1940 (Box 48, Folder 1292-1295)
    - Science of Society, 1939-1941 (Box 48, Folder 1296-1298)
    - Anthropology, 1940-1941, undated (Box 48, Folder 1299-1304)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 48, Folder 1305)
    - Gradelists (Box 48, Folder 1306)
  - Examinations
    - For Anthropology 10a, 1914-1932, undated (Box 49, Folder 1307)
    - On Extra Readings for Anthropology 10a, undated (Box 49, Folder 1308)
    - For Mental Outfit, 1911, 1913, 1915, 1917, 1922, 1924, 1926 (Box 49, Folder 1309)
    - For Self-Maintenance of Society, 1913, 1918, 1923, 1925 (Box 49, Folder 1310)
    - For Self-Perpetuation, 1912, 1918, undated (Box 49, Folder 1311)
    - For Sociological Systems, 1911, 1915, 1920, 1922, 1926, undated (Box 49, Folder 1312)
    - For Science of Society, 1911-1932, undated (Box 49, Folder 1313)
    - On Extra Readings for Science of Society, undated (Box 49, Folder 1314)
    - For Graduate Course in Science of Society, 1928-1936 (Box 49, Folder 1315)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified examinations, 1920-1927, undated (Box 49, Folder 1316)
- William Graham Sumner Club, 1914-1949; Series IV; 1.3 linear feet (3 boxes)
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically.
  Publications is arranged chronologically.
  Lists, Notes, and Financial Records is arranged chronologically.
  (*) Ten or More Items
  - Correspondence
    - William Graham Sumner Club (*), 1914-1937 March (Box 50, Folder 1317-1360)
    - William Graham Sumner Club (*), 1937 May-1939 (Box 50, Folder 1361-1361a)
      See also: box 55, folder 1460
    - William Graham Sumner Club (*), 1940-1948 November (Box 51, Folder 1362-1392)
    - William Graham Sumner Club (*), 1949 January-Jun, undated (Box 51a, Folder 1393-1393b)
    - Constitution and By-Laws of the Associates in the Science of Society at Yale University, typescript, undated (Box 51a, Folder 1393c)
    - William Graham Sumner Club, Constitution and By-Laws, Articles of Association, carbon typescripts, [1940] (Box 51a, Folder 1394)
    - Sumner centennial 1840-1940 (*), 1938-1940 Nov, [1940], undated (Box 51a, Folder 1394a-1395a)
    - Clippings (*), 1936-1942, undated (Box 51a, Folder 1395b)
  - Publications
    - Bulletin of the Associates in the Science of Society
      - Volume I, numbers 1-4, 1931-1932 (Box 52, Folder 1396)
      - Volume II, numbers 1-4, 1932-1933 (Box 52, Folder 1397)
      - Volume III, numbers 1-4, 1933-1934 (Box 52, Folder 1398)
      - Volume IV, numbers 1-4, 1934-1935 (Box 52, Folder 1399)
      - Volume V, numbers 1-4, 1935-1936 (Box 52, Folder 1400)
      - Volume VI, numbers 1-4, 1937 (Box 52, Folder 1401)
      - Volume VII, numbers 1-4, 1938 (Box 52, Folder 1402)
      - Volume VIII, numbers 1-4, 1939 (Box 52, Folder 1402)
      - Volume IX, numbers 1-4, 1940 (Box 52, Folder 1402)
    - Bulletin of the William Graham Sumner Club
      - Volume XI, numbers 1-4, 1941-1942 (Box 52, Folder 1403)
      - Volume XII, numbers 1-3, 5, 1942-1943 (Box 52, Folder 1404)
      - Volume XIII, numbers 1-6, 1943-1944 (Box 52, Folder 1405)
      - Volume XIV, numbers 1-4, 1944-1945 (Box 52, Folder 1406)
      - Volume XV, numbers 1-4A, 1945-1946 (Box 52, Folder 1407)
      - Volume XVI, numbers 1-4, 1947 (Box 52, Folder 1408)
      - Volume XVII, numbers 1-4, 1948 (Box 52, Folder 1409)
      - Volume XVIII, numbers 1-3, 1949 (Box 52, Folder 1410)
  - Lists, Notes and Financial Records
    - Lists of subscribers to the Bulletin of the Associates in the Science of Society, 1936-1941 (Box 52, Folder 1411)
    - Membership lists of the William Graham Sumner Club, 1931-1939, undated (Box 52, Folder 1412)
    - List of Sheffield Scientific School alumni, undated (Box 52, Folder 1412)
    - Financial records of the William Graham Sumner Club, 1936-1947 (Box 52, Folder 1413-1414)
    - Contract: Yale University Press, 1943 (Box 52, Folder 1415)
    - William Graham Sumner Club lists and notes, 1944, 1947, undated (Box 52, Folder 1416)
- Financial Records, 1902-1956; Series V; 0.5; (1 box)
  Financial Records is arranged by form: notebooks, receipts, checks, royalty statements.
  - Financial records: notebook, 1912-1938 (Box 53, Folder 1417-1419)
  - Financial records, 1949-1956 (Box 53, Folder 1420)
  - Receipts, 1901-1956 (Box 53, Folder 1421)
  - Receipts from Ford Brothers, Inc. - Fuel Oil Service, 1951-1956 (Box 53, Folder 1422)
  - Receipts, 1903-1951 (Box 53, Folder 1423)
  - Insurance and health care records, 1915-1956 (Box 53, Folder 1424)
  - Canceled checks, 1914-1956 (Box 53, Folder 1425-1426)
  - Sales statements: Yale Cooperative Corporation, 1909, 1911, 1913-1916, 1922-1924 (Box 53, Folder 1427)
  - Royalty Statements: The Macmillan Company, 1915-1918, 1920-1922 (Box 53, Folder 1428)
  - Royalty and copyright statements: Ginn and Company, 1909-1911, 1913-1918, 1921-1923 (Box 53, Folder 1429)
  - Royalty statements: Yale University Press, 1914, 1923-1924 (Box 53, Folder 1430)
  - Royalty statements: Longmans, Green and Co., 1902-1917 (Box 53, Folder 1431-1432)
  - Contracts: Yale University Press, 1942, undated (Box 53, Folder 1433)
- Memorabilia, 1885-1957; Series VI; 1 linear feet (3 boxes)
  Writings of Others is arranged by subject.
  Drawings and Photographs is arranged chronologically.
  Tributes to Keller is arranged chronologically.
  - Writings of Others
    - Articles about William Graham Sumner collected by Albert G. Keller, 1885-1918, 1940, undated (Box 54, Folder 1434)
    - Newspaper clippings about Clarence Day, Jr. collected by Albert Keller, 1919, 1935, 1936, 1948, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 1435)
    - Book reviews and miscellaneous articles collected by A. G. Keller, 1908-1955 (Box 54, Folder 1436)
    - Essay: "Examen for a Loose Screw", TMs, post-1920 (Box 54, Folder 1437)
    - Lecture outlines by Yale professors on the "Introduction to the Social Sciences", 1924 (Box 54, Folder 1438)
    - Miscellaneous writings by others, 1894-1938, 1944-1954, undated (Box 54, Folder 1439-1442)
    - "Excerpts" from a variety of novels, undated (Box 54, Folder 1443)
    - Two hundred and ninety-eight quotations, undated (Box 54, Folder 1444)
    - The Colby Essays, Volumes I and II, edited by Clarence Day, Jr., 1926 (Box 54, Folder 1445)
    - Anonymous, "A Brief History of the Social Sciences at Yale University", mss., accompanying note cards on sociology courses at Yale, 1872-1937, [1942] (Box 54, Folder 1445a)
  - Drawings and Photographs
    - Drawings and notes by Clarence Day, Jr., 1904, 1911, 1915, undated (Box 55, Folder 1446)
    - Engravings: Nicholas Prejevalsky, Sir John Lubbock, Lewis H. Morgan, Paul Broca, and H. Humboldt, undated (Box 55, Folder 1447)
    - Photographs: Albert G. Keller, Edward Eagan and family, dinner of the William G. Sumner Club 1940 Oct 30, two unidentified photographs (Box 55, Folder 1448)
  - Tributes to Keller
    - Certificate: American Academy of Arts and Science, 1934 May 9 (Box 55, Folder 1449)
    - Invitations, cards, menus and other miscellaneous memorabilia, 1876-1952 (Box 55, Folder 1450)
    - Articles about A.G. Keller, 1908-1953 (Box 55, Folder 1451-1452)
    - Studies in the Science of Society presented to Albert G. Keller, TMs, 1937 (Box 55, Folder 1453-1459)
    - Studies in the Science of Society correspondence, 1936 March-1937 May (Box 55, Folder 1460)
      See also: box 50, folder 1358-1361
    - Keller Dinner Committee correspondence, 1941 October-1942 Jan, undated (Box 56, Folder 1461-1466)